<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>The Vickker </title>
    <link href="https://vickkerokc.github.io/vickker1/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://vickkerokc.github.io/vickker1" />
    <updated>2025-07-16T21:28:59-05:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Vicki Langford</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://vickkerokc.github.io/vickker1</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Becoming Congruent</title>
        <author>
            <name>Vicki Langford</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://vickkerokc.github.io/vickker1/becoming-congruent.html"/>
        <id>https://vickkerokc.github.io/vickker1/becoming-congruent.html</id>
            <category term="Blurbs"/>

        <updated>2025-03-05T05:06:00-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    My big realization this morning as I awakened was that. I'm not going to lie anymore. A lie for the right reason is still a lie and it eats at my soul. However I also do not have to confess my truths just because someone&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
  <p>
    My big realization this morning as I awakened was that.  I'm not going to lie anymore.  A lie for the right reason is still a lie and it eats at my soul. 
<br>
<br>However I also do not have to confess my truths just because someone asks.  
<br>
<br>It's no one's business.  
<br>Adultery is a made up crime.  A crime that is man made. And historically the woman is punished much more harshly than the man.  
<br>
<br>That is incongruent   
<br>That I no longer subscribe too. 
<br>
<br>So in the future, when pressed to confess, I will plead the fifth.  
<br>
<br>I shall be my beautiful sinful self. And I will be a loving kind person 
<br>And I will accept and forgive the petty crimes of my fellow humans because that is simply just part of life.  
<br>
<br>Those that judge can stand on their high horse, living incongruous and I will accept and forgive.
  </p>

  <p>
    And turn my lip so slightly as to hide the smile of recognition.
  </p>

  <p>
    &nbsp;No one is innocent.  
<br>
<br>
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Learning Love</title>
        <author>
            <name>Vicki Langford</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://vickkerokc.github.io/vickker1/learning-love.html"/>
        <id>https://vickkerokc.github.io/vickker1/learning-love.html</id>
            <category term="Blurbs"/>

        <updated>2024-09-22T23:24:00-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I thought being needed was love but that equation creates a loop that isn't solvable. being needed: I look for perceived needs and fill them, I have to keep filling to feel love, but then I get exhausted. Then I don't feel appreciated and that&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
  <p>
    I thought being needed was love but that equation creates a loop that isn't solvable. 
<br>
<br>being needed: 
<br>I look for perceived needs and fill them, I have to keep filling to feel love, but then I get exhausted. Then I don't feel appreciated and that turns to resentment and then that turns to guilt and lack so then I need to be needed and it starts all over again. 
<br>
<br>I need to be needed = love
<br>The other person needs to satisfy my need to be loved.&nbsp;
  </p>

  <p>
    
Read that again.&nbsp;&nbsp;
  </p>

  <p>
    It feels like love because filling <em>their </em>need actually satisfies <em>my </em>need to be needed.<br>
  </p>

  <p>
    I think being needed is love!!<br>
<br>This epiphany washed over me.&nbsp; Magically I now see their needs as <em>their </em>need. Period.&nbsp;
  </p>

  <p>
    Take a beat. Assess. Just because they 'need' doesn't mean I have to fill that need. Is it mine to fill? Is it someone else's? Is it realistic?
  </p>

  <p>
    I can monitor my giving.&nbsp; And now I am forming a&nbsp;healthy boundary. I can show love and not over give.&nbsp;&nbsp;
  </p>

  <p>
    <em>Full circle</em>:&nbsp; <em>The people that <u>love me</u> but <u>don't need me</u> I could not see.&nbsp;</em>&nbsp;<br>I could not see the people who didn't need me because that didn't register as love. Because I learned to believe that LOVE looked and felt like being needed and me fulfilling that need.&nbsp;
  </p>

  <p>
    I am now understanding love as something much more calm and peaceful.&nbsp;
  </p>

  <p>
    
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Ocean in Your Eyes</title>
        <author>
            <name>Vicki Langford</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://vickkerokc.github.io/vickker1/the-ocean-in-your-eyes.html"/>
        <id>https://vickkerokc.github.io/vickker1/the-ocean-in-your-eyes.html</id>
            <category term="Poems"/>

        <updated>2024-08-18T14:02:00-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I’m swimming in the ocean in your eyes It is vast and wide Forever it holds me I float in that ocean The waves carry me Gentle breezes Swaying to and fro Even when seas get stormy the sun shines brightly again And I’m still&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
  <p>
    I’m swimming in the ocean in your eyes
<br>It is vast and wide
<br>Forever it holds me 
<br>I float in that ocean
<br>
<br>The waves carry me 
<br>Gentle breezes
<br>Swaying to and fro
<br>
<br>Even when seas get stormy the sun shines brightly again
<br>And I’m still there floating in the ocean of your eyes
<br>
<br>It is a very comfortable place 
<br>Familiar and safe
<br>I’ve been here before caught in the ocean in your eyes
<br>
<br>Your ocean is expansive
<br>I’m a mere drop of water
<br>Part of something bigger than myself
<br>
<br>The ocean in your eyes is no ones to contain, to control
<br>I’m in awe and wonder
<br>
<br>I see myself in the ocean in your eyes
<br>I wail up in tears
<br>My eyes weep a drop and we swirl together
<br>Not knowing where one begins and the other ends
<br>
<br>Blissfully in wonderment, I witness the beauty and grace
<br>The power and force of the ocean in your eyes
<br>Mesmerized<br>
<br>I shake and tremble with ever-flowing love
<br>The ocean in your eyes belongs to no one
<br>
<br>Not everyone can see it
<br>Nor comprehend the grandeur
<br>Yet you offer it freely
<br>
<br>The ocean in your eyes knows no lack, no scarcity, no limits
<br>
<br>Boundless, formless, space, energy, infinity
<br>The ocean in your eyes reminds me we are not alone
<br>We are part of so much more
<br>
<br>I see also pain in the ocean in your eyes
<br>This conduit that transmits so easily the frequencies of everyone, everything
<br>The ocean in your eyes is a beautiful reflection back to those who are ready to see.
<br>I see myself in the ocean in your eyes in a way I’ve never seen before.
<br>
<br>I choose to see, to look, to feel and do my own work to heal
<br>
<br>You are safe behind the reflection of the ocean in your eyes
<br>You see people looking there, you see what they see, safely behind the reflection
<br>
<br>No one can own the ocean in your eyes
<br>They may try to siphon some for themselves or take a bucket full out
<br>
<br>The ocean in your eyes is abundance, your connection to source
<br>Ever present, it washes over you, it grounds you when you let it
<br>
<br>Thank you for showing me the ocean in your eyes
<br>For letting me swim and swirl
<br>Feel my respect and awe, my deep admiration
<br>
<br>For the ocean in your eyes does not belong to me, to anyone
<br>
<br>The ocean in your eyes is freedom 
<br>Let the ocean breeze guide your waves
<br>Your connection to source, your compass&nbsp;<br>
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Whirlwind</title>
        <author>
            <name>Vicki Langford</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://vickkerokc.github.io/vickker1/whirlwind.html"/>
        <id>https://vickkerokc.github.io/vickker1/whirlwind.html</id>
            <category term="Poems"/>

        <updated>2024-06-02T14:11:00-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I'm in a whirlwind Tossing and turning Flying high Breaking barriers Freeing my mind Taking flight Anything is possible So many layers Bottom up Top down My eyes are open Seeing it all Flying by Grooving Leaving the past Reshaping Rebuilding Regenerating I'm in a&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
  <p>
    I'm in a whirlwind 
<br>Tossing and turning 
<br>Flying high
<br>Breaking barriers 
<br>Freeing my mind
<br>
<br>Taking flight
<br>Anything is possible 
<br>So many layers
<br>Bottom up
<br>Top down
<br>
<br>My eyes are open 
<br>Seeing it all
<br>Flying by
<br>Grooving 
<br>Leaving the past
<br>
<br>Reshaping 
<br>Rebuilding 
<br>Regenerating
<br>
<br>I'm in a whirlwind 
<br>Moving fast
<br>Taking it slow
<br>Vibrating higher
<br>Than I ever know
<br>
<br>Life is meant to live
<br>Living is being alive
<br><br>Leave the old beliefs
<br>Let the whirlwind 
<br>Carry you away
<br>
<br>
<br>
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Lost in a storm</title>
        <author>
            <name>Vicki Langford</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://vickkerokc.github.io/vickker1/lost-in-a-storm.html"/>
        <id>https://vickkerokc.github.io/vickker1/lost-in-a-storm.html</id>
            <category term="Poems"/>

        <updated>2024-03-18T05:44:00-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Pitch black I was lost Lost in a storm Couldn’t see where I was heading I was in uncharted waters In the eye of the storm it didn’t feel like a storm There was a comfortable tension And day after day the goal was keeping&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
  <p>
    Pitch black
<br>I was lost
<br>Lost in a storm
<br>Couldn’t see where I was heading
<br>I was in uncharted waters
<br>
<br>In the eye of the storm it didn’t feel like a storm
<br>There was a comfortable tension
<br>And day after day the goal was keeping it taught
<br>
<br>Being a ballast
<br>Always struggling tugging pulling 
<br>This way and that
<br>Navigating the storm
<br>I was in the storm for so long
<br>All the effort felt safe, felt normal
<br>Until it didn’t 
<br>Then the exhaustion welled up
<br>I collapsed in a heap not understanding
<br>With these all too familiar sayings ringing in my head
<br>“Is this all there is?”
<br>“There’s got to be a better way.”
<br>
<br>Like reaching the top of the mountain 
<br>and seeing the breathtaking vision 
<br>but realizing you lost yourself along the way. 
<br>
<br>Letting go of the struggle started off very slow
<br>First I just did less and less 
<br>And waited
<br>
<br>Sometimes I waited a long time
<br>For something to happen that called me back to deck
<br>Back into action
<br>
<br>And then I waited again
<br>In that waiting I started to hear the call of myself
<br>The buried self long forgotten
<br>Another crash
<br>Called to action
<br>But I was a bit different
<br>Something shifted ever so slightly
<br>The other crew members noticed
<br>I was becoming less and less concerned about maintaining equilibrium 
<br>I was becoming more and more curious about navigating differently
<br>I was seeing more clearly
<br>The storm isn’t that bad
<br>I stopped being a ballast
<br>I began to question my programming, my role.
<br>Why was i a ballast
<br>Was the ballasting I was doing correct
<br>Was I helping
<br>What was I accomplishing
<br>
<br>The more I questioned
<br>The less i did
<br>Which caused the captain and crew to not be happy with me
<br>What was going on with me, they were curious
<br>Why are you acting like this
<br>Are you depressed? Are you Mad?
<br>As in crazy
<br>Was I? 
<br>I was definitely navigating uncharted territory
<br>Leading into a storm of a different kind
<br>
<br>The change of heading
<br>The different tactics
<br>Caused me to realize the captain and crew didn’t trust me
<br>They trusted the previous condition 
<br>They status quo
<br>My value to them was lost
<br>
<br>I’m really lost now
<br>I haven’t found me yet
<br>And now I’ve lost their faith
<br>Who am I? What am I doing? 
<br>These thoughts crashed so loudly as waves in the night
<br>
<br>Uncharted waters
<br>I lean into my faith and surrender
<br>It only takes a few days
<br>In the distance, ever so faint
<br>I see it
<br>I see a small light
<br>I set a course
<br>
<br>
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The dysfunctional quagmire of the status quo</title>
        <author>
            <name>Vicki Langford</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://vickkerokc.github.io/vickker1/the-dysfunctional-quagmire.html"/>
        <id>https://vickkerokc.github.io/vickker1/the-dysfunctional-quagmire.html</id>
            <category term="Blurbs"/>

        <updated>2024-02-02T23:37:00-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    To leave the comfort of the old sh*t requires some gumption and the willingness to let go of old opinions. Which kinda sums up my day. Which wraps up another layer of the life I'm moving on from. These are not easy things. They are&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
  <p>
    To leave the comfort of the old sh*t requires some gumption and the willingness to let go of old opinions.
<br>
<br>Which kinda sums up my day.  Which wraps up another layer of the life I'm moving on from.  
<br>
<br>These are not easy things.  
<br>They are uncomfortable and these actions tend to upset the dysfunctional quagmire of status quo 
<br>
<br>-huh-&nbsp;<br>-what-<br>I was just rambling writing, and&nbsp;damn. 
<br>"The dysfunctional quagmire of the status quo"... 
<br><br>Fkn love that line.&nbsp;
  </p>

  <p>
    
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>The Human Harmony</title>
        <author>
            <name>Vicki Langford</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://vickkerokc.github.io/vickker1/the-human-harmony.html"/>
        <id>https://vickkerokc.github.io/vickker1/the-human-harmony.html</id>
            <category term="Poems"/>

        <updated>2024-01-28T22:49:00-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I'm raw material Ready to shape shift Aware of the layers Taking on shapes To navigate experience To experience life There's a pattern A resonance to our life To the human condition We are played Or we become a player Awareness of the patterns Allows&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
  <p>
    I'm raw material
<br>Ready to shape shift
<br>Aware of the layers 
<br>Taking on shapes 
<br>To navigate experience
<br>To experience life
<br>
<br>There's a pattern
<br>A resonance to our life
<br>To the human condition
<br>We are played
<br>Or we become a player
<br>
<br>Awareness of the patterns
<br>Allows us to navigate the layers
<br>The more aware
<br>The more the symphony plays 
<br>The beautiful symphony of life
<br>The chords their harmony
<br>Their dissonance
<br>
<br>The emotional chords of love and loss
<br>Seeking and wanting connection
<br>Slightly out of tune
<br>
<br>Ah, but life is a self correcting chorus 
<br>And we all have our beautiful part to play
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>A Good Life</title>
        <author>
            <name>Vicki Langford</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://vickkerokc.github.io/vickker1/a-good-life.html"/>
        <id>https://vickkerokc.github.io/vickker1/a-good-life.html</id>
            <category term="Lyrics"/>

        <updated>2024-01-25T13:47:00-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Intro I wanted more, From life I didn’t get to do, everything, i wanted Cuz I wanted more, from life I always thought there’d be more time V1 I overcame, my childhood burdens I learned to, take care of myself One step at a time,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <hr class="separator separator--dots" />

  <p>
    <strong>Intro</strong>
<br>I wanted more, From life
<br>I didn’t get to do, everything, i wanted
<br>Cuz I wanted more, from life
<br>I always thought there’d be more time
<br>
<br><strong>V1</strong>
<br>I overcame, my childhood burdens
<br>I learned to, take care of myself
<br>One step at a time, I improvised, Improved my life, My circumstance
<br>Moved to Hollywood, the land of dreams
<br>Made my way, all the way, to Beverly Hills
<br>Swimming pools, movie stars
<br>
<br><strong>PRE</strong>
<br>
<br><strong>V2</strong>
<br>I desired, the finer things in life,
<br>I worked hard, so I could fit in
<br>One event at a time, I connected, saved my money, got fancy clothes
<br>Met movie stars, the rich and famous
<br>Before you know it, I hobnobbing
<br>Beach parties, private clubs
<br>
<br><strong>PRE</strong>
<br><br><strong>Chorus</strong>
<br>Oh so grateful for a good life
<br>Wasn’t always easy, this life
<br>Oh so grateful for a good life
<br>Wasn’t always easy, this life
<br>
<br><strong>V3</strong>
<br>Later in life, I found true love
<br>4th of July, sucking on toes
<br>Hawaii life, became your wife
<br>Our love story, so real, so true
<br>Met all your friends, over all night dinners
<br>Now I’m a valley girl, with 9 step kids
<br>Movie nights, Cadillac margaritas
<br>
<br><strong>Bridge</strong>
<br>Our story, ended way to soon, 
<br>So grateful, life with you
<br>
<br><strong>Chorus out</strong>&nbsp;<br>
  </p>
<hr class="separator separator--dots" />

  <p class="msg msg--highlight">
    Lyrics: Vicki Langford.&nbsp; Guitar: Marty Simon.&nbsp; Drums:&nbsp; Zev Stein.&nbsp;
  </p>
<div><p><audio loading="lazy" controls>
  <source src="2024-0125-A_Good_Life.mp3" type="audio/mpeg">
  Your browser does not support the audio element.
</audio></p></div>

  <p class="msg msg--info">
    This audio file is from a recording i did using bandlab with just the guitar track and then my vocal.&nbsp; At the time the band practices stopped, I hadn't written lyrics for this piece.&nbsp; This piece ended up being very special as it became a tribute to my sister, Jeannie Larson, who passed in Nov 2023.&nbsp; I got the bulk of the song done in Sep 2023 and my sister was able to hear that.&nbsp; I finished this the night before and the morning of her burial in Jan 2024.&nbsp; This was played at her service.&nbsp; #love
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>My Warm Bed</title>
        <author>
            <name>Vicki Langford</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://vickkerokc.github.io/vickker1/my-warm-bed.html"/>
        <id>https://vickkerokc.github.io/vickker1/my-warm-bed.html</id>
            <category term="Poems"/>

        <updated>2024-01-15T22:41:00-06:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    I've made it to my warm bed. Curating ones bed. The bed itself. soft, firm or somewhere in-between The sheets. sheen, softness, texture The covers. heaviness, thickness, layers The pillows. firmness, flexibility, quantity Curled up or sprawled across It's a very personal space Our comfortable&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
  <p>
    I've made it to my warm bed.  
<br>
<br>Curating ones bed.  
<br><br>The bed itself. soft, firm or somewhere in-between
<br>
<br>The sheets. sheen, softness, texture
<br>
<br>The covers. heaviness, thickness, layers<br>
<br>The pillows.  firmness, flexibility, quantity<br><br>Curled up or sprawled across<br><br>It's a very personal space
<br>
<br>Our comfortable space.
<br>Comfy cozy
<br>Warm snuggly
<br>Sleepy drifting<br><br>Safe<br>
  </p>

  <p>
    
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>In the pause of nature</title>
        <author>
            <name>Vicki Langford</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://vickkerokc.github.io/vickker1/in-the-pause-of-nature.html"/>
        <id>https://vickkerokc.github.io/vickker1/in-the-pause-of-nature.html</id>
            <category term="Blurbs"/>

        <updated>2023-07-07T22:52:00-05:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Sitting in the window seat the window open listening to the wind feeling the rain watching for lightening flashes hearing the thunder rumbles the expansion of what we thought about what we are literally our energy field extends limitless across the earth and beyond infinity&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                
  <p>
    Sitting in the window seat
<br>the window open<br>listening to the wind
<br>feeling the rain
<br>watching for lightening flashes
<br>hearing the thunder rumbles
<br>
<br>the expansion of what we thought
<br>about what we are
<br>literally our energy field extends limitless 
<br>
<br>across the earth and beyond
<br>
<br>infinity let me on&nbsp;<br>
  </p>

  <p>
    
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
